Hello everyone, in the 2026.0 version, when applying hair loss or hair material, it can maintain the effect of the gap line and the sticker can be seen.
In the past, these details were often blocked by hair.
This update ensures that the craft structure is still visible and the sticker can be perfectly displayed on the surface of the hair,
thereby improving the visual quality and authenticity of hair-dyeing clothing, hair-dyeing toys, and home-made fabric.
Let's take a look at how it works.
When you use the editor's sewing line tool to select a fabric type and set it as a single or multiple sewing lines of a hair-dyeing or hair-dyeing only dyeing clothing,
a new hair-dyeing reduction option will appear in the property editor.
In this thickness section, you can adjust the width from 0 mm to 100 mm.
The unit will be set based on the unit of the user, which is used to adjust the area where the hair will be removed.
The higher the value, the larger the hair-free area.
In this example, I will set this value to 2 mm.
By using the gradient setting under the neckline, you can adjust the distance between the hair-dyeing area and the hair-dyeing area to a range of 0 to 100.
Since the material type of this fabric is hair-dyeing, the result will be visible immediately in the 3D window,
but you can also check the final result in the rendering window to get a higher sense of reality.
In the previous CLO version, the sticker will be applied to hair-dyeing or hair-dyeing materials.
Usually, it will cause the hair to overlap and block the sticker, making it invisible in the rendering window.
For example, after applying the hair-dyeing material, although the 2D window shows a embroidery sticker,
it will not appear in the 3D window.
If it is a hair-dyeing material, it is also invisible in the 3D window.
In the new version, if you use the adjustment sticker tool to select the sticker,
you will notice that the hair-dyeing reduction option has been added to the property editor.
When the sticker is applied to the hair-dyeing clothing, this option will be defaulted.
You can click on the button.
Here, you can activate or stop this option by clicking on the box.
When the hair-dyeing is used, it seems that the hair-dyeing has been trimmed in the sticker area,
so that the sticker is completely visible in the 3D window and rendering window.
Please note that according to the shape and parameters of the hair,
such as length and curve, the hair-dyeing may still cover the sticker in some areas.
Please note this when using long hair-dyeing or long hair-dyeing materials.
If necessary, please consider adjusting the parameters.
In addition, if your pattern has non-transparent information, the hair will be visible in transparent areas.
For example, this sticker center is completely transparent, so the hair will be visible in the specific area.
With the introduction of this function in the 2026.0 version, you can better control the design of hair-dyeing materials.
Whether it is a clothing accessory, a hair-dyeing toy, or a home-made imitation,
while maintaining the seam line and the sticker are perfectly visible on the surface of the hair,
you can completely control the length and change of the hair,
thereby improving the quality and accuracy of the design.
In the 2026.0 version, in addition to displaying or hiding specific measurement values,
it also increases the possibility of displaying measurement points in the style picture rendering.
The goal is to obtain more technical and information-based style picture rendering,
and accurately display the measurement value of the clothing.
Let's take a look at it through an example.
Some measurement points have already been added to this file,
which are used to determine the measurement size and position of the clothing.
After the fire style picture is rendered, the line contains the 2D measurement size option.
By clicking the eye icon, you can switch the display or hide of the 2D measurement size.
You will notice that the measurement size of the corresponding measurement point will be displayed with it.
If necessary, you can change the line color and its opacity.
This option will apply to the visualization of all measurement points in the project.
However, if you need to hide any of them, you can use the measurement point table.
You can find the same eye icon next to each measurement point.
All you have to do is click the measurement point you want to hide to get a clearer and more reasonable style picture rendering.
By using the 2026.0 version, your style picture rendering is more accurate and reasonable than ever before.
Now let's start to completely control your measurement point visibility and simplify your technical package.
In the previous CLO version, when the rendering has a reflective material,
for example, the image of metal and glass,
the use of the ground shadow option will lead to the environment of the ground shadow appearing in the reflection of the object.
In the 2026.0 version, you can now remove these shadows from the reflection,
while still maintaining the shadow on the ground,
allowing us to see an improvement in this image.
As you can see, this virtual model is made of glass,
and has a mirroring effect that forms a reflective light on a layer of metal.
In addition, the attached metal material on the case will also reflect light.
In the light attribute of the window rendering,
the use of the ground shadow option will apply the shadow on the floor.
However, because this shadow has a reflection of the environment on the surface,
this will lead to the image being visible in the reflection of the virtual model and the object.
From the beginning of this version,
the bottom of the ground shadow added a non-reflective option.
When you activate this option by selecting the frame,
you need to press the synchronize rendering button to apply this change.
You will notice that the environment of the ground shadow is no longer in the glass and metal material,
and the reflection is no longer in the glass and metal material.
Now, by using the new function of Claw2026.0,
which does not participate in the reflection of the ground shadow,
you can achieve a surprising and clear reflection,
and no needless shadows,
and thus further enhance your rendering experience.